I have one day to make a full
Hermitcraft episode. That is going to be
tough. So, we're gonna see what we can
do in one day. If you've watched
Hermitcraft, you know it takes normally
2 to 3 days minimum to get an episode
done. So, we're going to have to
basically speedun an episode of
Hermitcraft today in order to get it
ready. And the first thing I've got to
do is get my boots back. For that, I
need levels. And for levels, I need to
trade. So, let's upgrade these boots and
get them enchanted. Now, if we're going
to go and put some enchantments on these
boots, there's only one place to do it,
and that is Lookie lookie at my bookie.
Hold the phone. What is this? Is this
burn stick? Oh, there's Oh, there's
more. Is this burn stick? Is this burn
stick? What on earth is a burn stick? I
I don't know.
Is this a burn stick? It certainly is
sticks that are being burnt. They're on
all of them. Is this burn stick? Do they
mean the chimneys or the campfires?
Is this burn? And why is there sometimes
a space and sometimes not? Is this burn
stick? I honestly have no idea. Yes,
I I think it is. Yes. I don't know how
to answer this. I don't know who's done
this either. How am I supposed to answer
this question? It's on every single one.
Look at this. Is this burnt stick? Yes,
this is burnstick. I guess I just got
hideously distracted. Okay, we're off to
the shopping district cuz we need to
enchant our boots. Our wee little boots.
And actually, we can Oh, wow.
Sparkly trees. The shopping district has
so much money, it's growing on trees. I
was going to say we could check if
Scar's seen our invitation.
Doesn't Doesn't look like it. They're
still in there chilling. I've got to do
something. Wow. I wish there was a chair
here. That'll do. So, we want a quick
trip to Lookie Lookie at My Bookie.
Probably the most profitable shop.
Lookie at my Cookie opening soon. Now,
that sounds like a deal. So, we're going
to need an unbreaking book.
He hasn't even cashed out. This is
definitely more successful than the
barge and probably way easier. We need a
feather falling. Probably a depth
strider protection. And of course, I
don't have enough levels. Hang on. I've
just flown all across the shopping
district and not even realized the
mcelium's gone. It's all bright green
grass. Oh, except over there. It looks
so weird. In a good way. It looks I
don't know. I can't decide whether I
like it or not. At first I was like,
"Yeah, I want all the mycelium gone."
But now I see it in green. It's I'm just
not used to it. But I think it is a
better change overall. Wow. This must
have taken a stupid amount of time. And
look at this road. How did I miss all
this? I saw the trees with the diamonds,
of course, but I missed all this. Look
at that. A proper prominard. A nice
street. And the path goes down into my
shop, which is quite cool. Whoa. Whoa.
Whoa. The barge. Burn. Burn stick. Burn
stick. Are these These are all burn
stick questions again. They are all on
top of campfires. I'll be honest. I have
no idea what a burn stick is. But yes,
this is a campfire. Got to tidy up my
shop now. It's a lot of burn sticks.
Yes,
burns.
I don't really know what else to say.
Right. So, while we're here, we'll do
the rounds. We are running low on quite
a lot of stuff, particularly sand. We
didn't sell any Netherite stuff, but we
did sell some of our regular stuff.
Okay, so job one ticked off the list for
the start of this one day episode. I am
in a mad rush to try and get everything
done. We need some more levels so that
we can enchant it up. And to be honest,
I'm a little bit flustered. I don't
really know what to do. I need to go and
finish my mansion. That's what I need to
do. So, let's head over to the upside
down and get cracking on that mansion. I
need some sort of Nether song to get get
me through this tunnel every time I use
it. It's pretty painful. Flying flying
in the Nether. Flying flying in the
Nether. Flying flying in the Nether. Or
am I falling? Falling in the Nether.
Falling falling in the Nether. Oh, thank
goodness we're here. I also need a
better system than going into my farm
and falling down. I need to get I need
to get a move on basically and sort this
out. It's such a mess. And another
ghast. So much to do. So little time.
But actually since last episode, I've
realized there's a few rules to the
upside down and there's absolutely
nowhere that they're written. So, I
think before we get into the time lapse,
we need to kind of set this in motion in
some way. So, maybe hanging somewhere
around the middle. Let's try and line it
up at least a little bit with my
mansion. So, perhaps here we'll make a
little hanging platform. So, a little
temporary platform here. I mean, it's
it's literally just me and kind of
B-Dubz that's in the Nether. So, I don't
think we need to worry about making it
too pretty. At least not for now. This
also gives me a good chance to use some
of these chains. And now we create a
board the upside down rules for all
citizens. So what I'm thinking is number
one is the ultimate rule. Do not AFK.
It's a pretty simple rule. And number
two is all new citizens must be pranked.
So those are the two rules at the
moment. Since B-Dubz is the new citizen
in the upside down, he gets to do rule
number three. Now, here's where it gets
dangerous and interesting. BDubz can put
any rule he likes. Literally anything.
The more creative he is, the more
dangerous this gets. And if Scar comes
along, he can make the fourth rule. And
so on and so forth, depending on how
many people take up the invitation. And
we may even invite a couple more people
at the end of this episode. So, what
we're going to end up with hopefully is
a community of weird upside down
buildings and the most ridiculous rules
you've ever seen. If you have any ideas
for crazy rules, it could be anything
like citizens must not refer to each
other by their Minecraft names. They
must come up with nicknames for
everyone. And then we need to come up
with punishment. So, obviously, if you
AFK, you're going to get pranked. All
new citizens must be pranked. That's I
mean that's a given. And then we need to
kind of come up with some punishments.
That's this that's what this is
becoming. Uh I've just created the
weirdest community outpost in the Nether
I think ever. And I don't really know
why I've done this either. I just think
this will be a lot of fun. So what's
Beubs going to come up with? What's Scar
going to come up with? I don't know. But
you can help by making some suggestions.
And I think this will be so much fun. In
fact, it's so much fun, I'm a little bit
scared. But now we've set up the rules.
We've got a nice little hanging
platform. This place is going to get
busy and it's going to need tidying up.
It's going to need a lot of work, but I
am running out of time majorly. This is
still just a one-day episode. So,
without further ado, we must we must try
and make some progress here. I probably
don't have the time to do it, but we
must continue with the time lapse of the
upside down mansion. And in three, two,
one, let's go.
[Music]
No,
I'm blowing up my own stuff. No,
[Music]
that's enough gas. No. Whoa.
enough.
Oh, I'm having a I'm
Oh, no. No. Had enough. Oh, I just I
just finished all this. After that rude
interruption, I have completed another
section of the upside down mansion. I
did this in such a rush. I ran out of
certain blocks and I've had to stop. And
also, this represented two hours. I
mean, seriously, making an episode of
Hermitcraft in one day is just insane.
The fact that I managed to sacrifice a
few hours to do this is quite something.
Now, I'm only adding to the issue that
there are multiple places for mobs to
spawn, but we will sort that out another
time. And this time, there's a back, a
full intact back of the mansion. And
then we're gonna make this our interior
and probably use that door. So that
means I will take this down. But I want
to get back to the overworld now as I
feel like I've done everything I can
here. I've got a delivery of some sand
to make for the barge. And I feel I feel
like we can make a couple more
invitations to the upside down. We've
obviously invited B-Dubz and he's
accepted. And we've obviously invited
Scar and he's somehow missed our
invitation. I don't know how, but he's
missed it. So, I feel like we should
slowly, slowly, slowly invite more and
more people to the upside down
and get this crazy rule train on the go.
Oh. Ow.
Why isn't Why is it not going?
No,
I've got such a long way to go. I
literally don't have time for this. I
literally don't. Wow, this is weird.
Look, it looks like if you stare at my
character, it looks like I'm slowly
getting closer and closer and closer,
but I'm not. That's like a weird optical
illusion. And now we're walking, walking
in the Nether. Walking walking in the
Nether.
Help me. the light at the end of the
tunnel. It's nearly We're nearly there.
Killing those. I've got three
durability. That's all I need. And now
we trade to fix our elytra.
When I make a proper pigman farm, the XP
won't be an issue. Actually, it looks
like I've got boxes of potential stock
everywhere.
So, this might be a good opportunity to
go and fill up the barge with various
items. And if I'm going to do more
invitations,
I need more green heads. I I've done
this like three times now, but I keep
running out. I need a stock of green
heads.
So, you know what we got to do? We got
to go and ask Mumbo to kill us again. In
which case, we we need to do it a little
bit differently this time. Let's go and
see if we can find Mumbo. He's usually
at his base in some capacity. Can't find
Mumbo anywhere, but I did see a floating
Iskall over yonder. Looks like he's just
busy doing his thing. So, we'll do what
we always do. Fly in without him
noticing, hopefully. Put all our stuff
in a chest.
There we go. All our stuff. Set respawn.
And then slowly approach
It It just says It just says,
"Yeah, he's got it."
That one says, "Kill me."
Is he going to hes No. There was a
slight hes there was a slight
hesitation.
There was a slight hesitation.
Okay. Lol. Again. Again. I need to find
new and inventive ways of getting killed
by my friends.
Wow.
There has to be a better way of getting
your your head in this game.
Now he's got he's got the idea now. We
put on all our stuff and we vamoose out
of here. So, I'm planning on inviting
quite a lot of people to the upside down
iskal included at some point, but I want
to pace it as pace it. Whose base is
this? Oh, it's Corales's base. That
means we're on the right track. So, the
person that I want to invite next is
actually Etho, who I haven't really
interacted with much this season. So,
it' be interesting to see if he decides
to come to the upside down or not. I
have a feeling he would come up with
some ridiculous rule. And that's that's
kind of why I want to invite him just to
see what he comes up with. I'm lost.
Aha, there it is. Ethos
base of madness. I'm not going to do a
delivery green for this one. I'm going
to do something slightly different. I'm
actually going to make a dispenser of
some kind. So, I'll do a dropper down
like this. We'll do a test with a green
head and then we put the mystery button.
Now, I don't know if Etho will actually
accept the invitation to the upside
down. I don't really know what Etho
does. It seems like he just does madness
if I'm honest.
So, let's see if this works. Pop. There
it is. Out of the ground. That's exactly
what I wanted. Imagine this mystery
button and you get a green head. Now to
find an anvil in this madness.
I've renamed this green head. Join the
upside down.
No. No, I didn't. I used my last level
to rename that head. And now
Oh, for goodness sake.
I don't have time for this. Okay, let's
try this again. Done. Done. Done.
And done. And then we'll tempt him with
mysterious button. Press it. Okay, that
took far longer than I thought. Let's
get back to what we were going to do,
which is restock the barge really
quickly. Let's do some quick stocking
cuz I know that there's some things that
we're just completely out of and I'm
going away and I don't have time to
restock it while I'm gone.
[Music]
That's about as much stocking as I can
do before I have to go. Now, clearly
Scar has spent a long time making this
into grass as we said earlier, but I
just had a thought and I thought it'd be
quite funny. I don't know if you'll
notice. Maybe he will, maybe he won't,
but we're going to start small.
Just a few blocks. We'll plant some
mycelium.
You can never get rid of the mcelium.
The mcelium resistance. The longer Scar
doesn't notice, the bigger this patch is
going to get. And we'll see. I don't
know. We'll just see what we'll see what
happens. He might notice and get rid of
it immediately. My plan this episode was
to expand the barge, but I clearly
haven't got time for that. Normally,
that would take pretty much half a day.
But that doesn't mean that we can't
develop our shop. This is possibly my
favorite thing this season that I' I've
really enjoyed building, expanding, and
supplying the barge, and I think it's a
very popular shop. But I have another
idea. So, we have the backup box. I will
make one of those in the future. They
take quite a long time. But given the
fact that I've got a lot of grindstones,
I thought I could do something a little
bit more risky. And what we can do is
have mystery boxes. Mystery barge boxes.
That's what they are. Mystery barge
boxes. So, you have to pick your grian.
One of them will have the jackpot where
you make way more goods than you pay.
This looks This looks ridiculous. So,
the idea is you're not allowed to look
in the boxes. That's key. You are
absolutely not allowed to look in the
boxes. So, if I place them upside down,
I believe they can't be opened. That's
right. They can't be opened. And you
have to choose which Korean you're going
to take the mystery box from. So, this
is kind of a way for me to make some
diamonds and sell stock at the same
time. But some of them will give you
straight up some diamonds. So, let's
head back to the base and fill up these
boxes with junk. I I mean mystery items,
not junk.
So, the key here is to make sure that
each box has at least some valuables in.
And I'm sure I can make that happen
because I want people to come back and
shop there, including random player
heads. I could get rid of some lanterns.
Each one will be full of goodies. In
fact, I think this one is going to be
the jackpot box. In fact, the jackpot is
going to be so good, it gets a Netherite
ingot in there, and we all know how
valuable they are. There we go. That is
the Jackpot box. You get a random
assortment of really good stuff. Some of
it's not great. I mean, there's a bit of
stone in there. It's going to be a
smidge better than this one, which is
going to be mostly cobblestone. There'll
be some bits. Look, I'm going to put
ancient debris in there. There's gonna
be blaze rods. So, you're not going to
feel too cheated out of this. Maybe a
couple of diamonds get your money back,
but for the most part, this one's
probably going to be the worst one.
Like, a lot of a lot of junk items, but
that's what you do when you roll the
dice. In fact, some fireworks. A green
head.
Everyone needs a green head. In fact,
I'm going to bump up the jackpot box to
be really, really OP. That is such a
good amount. Just the netherite ingot
along with the diamonds. This makes it
OP. Absolutely OP. So, the next box I've
been filling up with general junk.
There's a few odds and sods.
Occasionally, stuff you use, you know,
like the golden carrots, but it's not
really going to be worth it. But, I want
to include some things like logs. Logs
are something you use all the time and
they cost a couple of diamonds a pop, so
then they're not underutilized by any
means. There we go. That one's done. And
then this one is definitely the junk one
where you you kind of lucked out. We'll
see how this all goes. If they're
popular, then I could I could get rid of
some I I mean mystery items quite often,
right? This one is the jackpot. And
we'll call them barge box. Jackpot.
Barge box. I love that. Naf. Naf barge
box. Naf. Naf just means rubbish. Bit a
bit a bit pants. And that leaves the
last one. And that leaves not bad barge
box. Now, what do we charge for this? So
going on the Nath barge box, you got a
couple of diamonds for the Shulker. One,
two, probably about 10 diamonds all in.
And most of that value comes from the
ancient debris. It is really filled with
junk. So that one will make me the most
profit. The jackpot barge box is
overvalued. So this this has got 19
diamonds plus two Netherite ingots,
which are worth a a massive amount. A
massive amount. They're worth like 30
diamonds a pop. So, you really win if
you win this one. And then this one
again, not so good. About about 12 to 15
diamonds. So, judging by the value of
the jackpot box, I would say whoa. No, I
wouldn't I wouldn't I wouldn't say wo.
I'd say I want to try 40 diamonds. 40
diamonds. Cuz if you win that jackpot
box, you are up like 60 plus diamonds. I
have no idea what order these are in.
I'm going to move these around off
camera. I'm going to cut it so no one
knows what order they're in. Okay. All
right. They are now all shuffled. And
they are now all placed. Now we need we
need a payment green. We'll put we'll
put him in here, shall we? We'll put the
payment green down there. There we go.
There we go. I think we've got this
sorted. Barge mystery boxes. Pay 42
diamonds and take a box. What's inside?
It's a mystery. Do not look before
buying. I know. I shouldn't have to say
that, but I really do. I really, really
do. It can be too tempting to just try
and open it beforehand.
So, if they were if they were really
going to have a look, they'd have to
break this and it would just be a whole
thing.
So, only I know which one is the
jackpot. And boy oh boy is it a good
jackpot. 42 diamonds is a lot to pay,
but that's also what you have to pay to
roll the dice for a good opportunity.
And there's a one in three chance. It's
a pretty good opportunity if you ask me.
And then there's a payment green down
there. Got to keep the barge fresh, but
I'm afraid that is all we have time for
today. It has been extremely difficult
and an extremely long day to get
everything done on this episode, but I
feel like we've done quite well despite
the time constraints, and we'll be back
in another episode
to carry on with our antics. There may
be a relatively long gap between
episodes. I can't guarantee it, just so
you're aware. So, I shall see you in the
next episode. And as always, thank you
very much for watching and goodbye.